<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Taming Knots</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Taming Knots</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 17:34:06 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Embracing Open Source Part 1: Ideology and Background</title>
      <link>/posts/2025-04-30-eos1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 17:34:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2025-04-30-eos1/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is the start of a series I’ve been wanting to write for a long time. I want to chronicle my journey with Linux, Free and Open Source Software, and taking back control over my data and my devices. If there’s a topic you are particularly interested in reading about in a future installment, please feel free to send me a message.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool Recommendations</title>
      <link>/posts/2025-04-12-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 17:34:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2025-04-12-tools/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every home should have a well stocked toolbox. From dorms to single family dwellings, everyone should have some basic tools to take care of emergency maintenance tasks. I&amp;rsquo;ve outlined below a few toolboxes that are ideal to serve each type of home. These lists are by no means exhaustive or apply to every situation. These are just my recommendations. These lists are also additive. Each list assumes that you already have the tools in the previous list. After the tool lists, there are two bonus lists. One is for additional items that will make things easier or faster. The other is for consumables.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stardew Valley 1.6 and Returning to the Simple Life</title>
      <link>/posts/2024-05-03-stardew/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 17:34:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2024-05-03-stardew/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is for 2024’s WeblogPoMo2024, a challenge to post every day in May. While I cannot commit to being able to write something every day, I will try to post something every week in May.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately I’ve been playing a lot of Stardew Valley’s 1.6 update. I absolutely adored the game when it originally released. It was the first ever game in the farming/life sim genre that I really stuck with for any significant length of time. I never really felt a pull to stick to it longterm, though and eventually fell off. I don’t really have forever games as much as games I come back to on a semiregular basis. Stardew has had two revisitations from me. The first one was when multiplayer was new. The second one was a couple years ago. While I enjoyed my time with the game both of those times, I never even completed the base game’s content again to get to the “new” stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tea, A Crash Course</title>
      <link>/posts/2024-04-13-tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 17:34:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2024-04-13-tea/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, folks I know will reach out to me asking for recommendations for this, that, or the other with regards to tea. While coffee lovers are a dime a dozen, especially in the US, the tea-loving community tends to be much smaller, though I have also found tea lovers to be a lot more interested in sharing their passion, rather than gatekeeping others. In that spirit, I want to put basically all of my tea knowledge down to paper, as it were, in order to share the love that I have for the breadth and depth of what at first appears to be a remarkably simple beverage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
